libertymutualgroup.com 2008-11-13

# Privacy

  | | |   
---  
| | Internet Privacy Policy  
  
---  
At Liberty Mutual we are dedicated to "Helping People Live Safer, More Secure Lives", our commitment to this message is carried through by "securing" your privacy on the web. Please read the following Internet Privacy Policy which explains how we at Liberty Mutual endeavor to build your trust and security through our web policies.

This Internet Privacy Policy applies to your visit to our web site [www.libertymutual.com](http://www.libertymutual.com/) and its affiliated sites. If you are an individual who has purchased an automobile, homeowners, or life insurance product from Liberty Mutual, or if you are a claimant under a disability policy, you or your employer have received or will be receiving in the mail a copy of Liberty Mutual's Privacy Disclosure Statement which contains important additional information about our privacy practices.  
  
Information Gathering  
  
---  
The level of information gathered by Liberty Mutual varies depending upon your request. The gathering of this information is designed with you in mind so that we can better service the products we offer you. Here are some examples of the types of information the Liberty Mutual web site collects if you choose to provide it: 

  1. "Contact Us" & Other Email Forms - Name & Email Address
  2. Request for Information Forms - Name & Mailing Address and/or Email Address
  3. Event Registration Forms - Name, Email Address, Mailing Address, Company, Title & Phone Number
  4. Newsletter Subscriptions - Name, Email Address, Mailing Address, Company, Title & Phone Number
  5. Resume Builder - Name, Address, Phone Number, Education, Certifications & Work Experience
  6. Auto Quoting Application - Name, Email Address, Mailing Address, Phone Number, Household and Driver information, Date of Birth, Vehicle and Coverage information, Discount eligibility information, Social Security Number, Consumer Reporting and Department of Motor Vehicle information
  7. Home Quoting Application - Name, Email Address, Mailing Address, Phone Number, Date of Birth, Property Address and Coverage information, Discount eligibility information, Social Security Number and Consumer Reporting information.
  8. Life Quoting Tool – Name, Email Address, Phone Number, Resident State, Date of Birth, Gender, Tobacco Use, Health and Other Personal Information for Estimated Underwriting Classification, Quoted Coverage Type, Amount and Premium
  9. Claims Service Online Reporting - Name, Address, Date of Birth, Policy Number, Phone, information about the claim or accident, information about the occupants of the other vehicle(s) (if applicable), the names of witnesses & other contact information
  10. Disability claim or Leave of Absense Online Reporting - Name, Address, Date of Birth, Phone, Employer, information about the claim or leave
  11. Safety & Health Online Catalog Order Form - Name, Email Address, Mailing Address, Company, Title, Phone Number
  12. Risk Strategies Library Registration - Name, Email Address, Mailing Address, Company, Title, Phone Number
  13. Online Customer Service - Name, Address, Phone Number, Policy Number, nature of request.
  14. Liberty Mutual Rewards - Name, Mailing Address, Email Address, Gender, Customer Status.
  15. eBilling - Name, Address, Phone Number, Email address, Social Security Number, Banking information, Date of Birth, Credit Card number if provided.

Using Information Gathered  
  
---  
The information Liberty Mutual collects is used to provide policy quotes when requested, administer insurance policies, answer questions or concerns, register participants for Liberty Mutual sponsored events, Liberty Mutual Rewards and provide information requested in a timely manner. We also collect information from prospective employees who are interested in applying for a position with Liberty Mutual. You can correct/update information supplied to www.libertymutual.com by sending an email to [corporateinfo@libertymutual.com >](mailto:corporateinfo@libertymutual.com) .

By using our website, Liberty Mutual is able to log general statistical information (from log files) such as: the domain name, IP address and browser type of our web site visitors. With the information gathered, we are better able to create a customized experience for your visit to our web site. The log file information does not contain personally identifiable information, such as name, address, phone, etc. and is used only in the aggregate.  
  
Cookies  
  
---  
What is a cookie? Cookies are sets of information that our web server assigns to you when you visit our web site. Cookies are used in a few areas of our site only for maintaining information between pages. They are not used for storing or tracking personal information from our customers. These cookies simply carry forward information that you submitted on one screen to the next screen, eliminating the need for redundant entry. These cookies do not gather any other personal information from you or your computer. You do have a choice whether or not to accept the cookie, however, if you reject the cookie or if cookies are disabled on your web browser, some parts of the web site will not be operable.  
About DoubleClick Spotlight tags  
  
---  
We use DoubleClick Spotlight Tags to collect anonymous (not personally identifiable) information about which advertisements and promotions bring users to our Web site.Liberty Mutual uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage our online advertising and promotions. These GIF files are provided by DoubleClick. These files enable DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements and promotions bring users to our Web site. With both cookies and Spotlight technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to <http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy>.  
Non Liberty Mutual Web Sites  
  
---  
Liberty Mutual is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other web sites on the Internet that may be linked to the Liberty Mutual web site. Please note that when you click on links to web sites outside of www.libertymutual.com, you are transferred to another web site that may not be under Liberty Mutual's control. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their privacy policy may differ from ours.  
Sharing Information Gathered  
  
---  
The Liberty Mutual web site is designed to give our customers, prospective customers, and visitors a confidential means of gathering information about our Company, services and products and for doing business with us over the Internet. Our site will only collect information that you voluntarily provide in order for us to service your request. If you have provided personal information on our web site in order to obtain a policy quote, administer your insurance policies, ask us a question, or register for a Liberty Mutual sponsored event, we may need to share that information with authorized third parties, if necessary to service your request. We do not sell any customer information to mailing list companies or telemarketing companies.  
Protecting Information Gathered and Security  
  
---  
Personal information you have provided is limited to employees and agents of Liberty Mutual who need to know that information in order to service your request. Liberty Mutual maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable regulations to guard your personal information. Liberty Mutual retains the information collected for as long as required or permitted by law or regulation.  
Notification of Changes  
  
---  
This Internet Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time. If we change our Internet Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this web site [www.libertymutual.com](http://www.libertymutual.com/). You may wish to visit this page periodically to review the most recent Internet Privacy Policy.  
This Internet Privacy Policy applies to the following Liberty Mutual Subsidiaries and Affiliates  
  
---  
Liberty Mutual Insurance Company  
Liberty Mutual Fire Insurance Company  
Liberty Mutual Mid-Atlantic Insurance Company  
Liberty Insurance Corporation  
LM Insurance Corporation  
The First Liberty Insurance Corporation  
Liberty Insurance Company of America  
Helmsman Management Services, Inc.  
Helmsman Insurance Agency, Inc.  
Liberty Life Assurance Company of Boston  
Liberty Life Securities LLC  
Liberty Lloyds of Texas Insurance  
Contact Information  
  
---  
Communications Department  
175 Berkeley Street  
Boston, MA 02116  
e-mail: [corporateinfo@libertymutual.com](mailto:corporateinfo@libertymutual.com)

Last modified on: September 5th, 2008
